The Ray Manley Photograph Collection 1958-1988
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Ray Manley Photograph collection 1958-1988 (bulk 1960-1969)
MS 462
Ray Manley
The bulk of this collection is from 1960-1970 and focuses on the work of Ray Manley, a commercial photographer in Tucson, Arizona. Subjects of the collection include many aspects of life at the University of Arizona, including special events on campus, various individuals, performances, ribbon cuttings, aerial photographs and campus buildings.
13.5
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None
Biographical Note
Ray Manley was a famous photographer whose images were published in Arizona Highways, Life, Look, Saturday Evening Post, Popular Science, National Geographic and his own books. He established Ray Manley Commercial Photography in 1953 with partners Naurice Koonce and Mickey Prim. Manley was born September 4, 1921 in Cottonwood, Arizona and died July 15, 2006. He took an early interest in photography and attended Arizona State College (later renamed Northern Arizona University) where he met his wife, Ruth. He was known as a persistent photographer who insisted upon photographing his subjects in the best light.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 6 series and subseries. The subseries are then arranged alphabetically by subject and chronologically by date into folders.
Series I: Campus Views
Series II: Departments
Series III: Campus Life
Series IV: Arts and Museums
Series VII: Buildings
Series VI: Various Shots of Arizona
Scope and Content Note
The Ray Manley commercial photography company was hired by various units and departments on the University of Arizona campus to document campus activities, from individuals, performances, ribbon cuttings, events, aerial photographs and campus buildings. The collection is primarily comprised of black and white 3x5 negatives, but includes a few color photographs. The collection includes images of departmental and student activities, musical and theater performances, award ceremonies, graduations, athletic events and photos of individuals such as “Pop McKale,” President Harvill, President Schaffer and his family, Senator Amherst and Robert Frost. Also included in the collection are student artwork, architectural models, museum displays, copies of paintings and photographs and miscellaneous museum objects. In Series VI there are various shots from around Tucson and Arizona. Images from multiple photographers employed by Ray Manley are included in this collection. The Ray Manley Collection contains the original envelopes for the negatives as they contain information regarding the purpose, dates and reasons for the photos being taken.
Access Terms
University of Arizona.
University Of Arizona -- Aerial Views.
University of Arizona. Museum of Art.
University of Arizona. School of Music.
University of Arizona -- Homecoming.
University of Arizona -- Buildings.
Athletics -- Arizona -- History.
Arizona State Museum.
University of Arizona -- Photograph collections
Container List
- Series I: Campus Views
  - Subseries 1: Aerial Views
    - Aerial views undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aerial views of campus 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Aerial views 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Aerial views 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Aerial views, and correspondence with Ray Manley Commercial Photography regarding jobs 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2: General Views
    - Around campus 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Around campus 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Around campus 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Around campus 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Around campus 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Around campus 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Around campus, 5th and Highland Avenue 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Cactus Garden 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series II: Departments
  - Subseries 1: Home Economics
    - Baby care undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bathing baby, cooking, dressmaking 1956-1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Class 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cooking, baby care and hand washing undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hand washing undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Hand and face washing undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hand washing undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Laboratory 1963-1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2: Architecture
    - Building models 1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Building models 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Building models, architecture classes, students 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Building models, drafting room 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Building models 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3: Astronomy and Climate Research
    - Cloud research 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Kitt Peak 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Kitt Peak 1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Flandreau Planetarium, memo to Ray Manley and Richard Norton regarding photography work 1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Lunar Lab 1958-1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Lunar Lab undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Solar Lab 1959, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Solar Lab 1961 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Solar Lab 1962-1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Steward Observatory 1963-1966, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4: Agriculture
    - Agriculture Winter School class 1962 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Experiments 1962 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Experiments and memo regarding photography of Sears Roebuck Foundation scholarship students in department of agriculture 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 5: Various Departments
    - Education Speech and Hearing Clinic 1962 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - KUAT 1962-1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - UA High School 1967 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - UA High School and handwritten pages regarding what photos ought to be taken of the High School 1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 6: Nursing and Medicine
    - Classes 1960-1962 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Classes 1962 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Conference 1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Students 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Medical School 1965-1971 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 7: Science and Engineering
    - Anthropology, sewage and tree ring laboratory 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Atom Smasher 1960-1968 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Chemistry Lab 1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Civil Engineering 1967 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Entomology and Herpology 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Geochronology 1962-1965 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Laboratories, Various 1961 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Laboratories, Various 1963 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Laboratories, Various 1963 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Laboratories, Various 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Nuclear Engineering 1962-1964 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Nuclear Engineering undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Zoology 1961 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Series III: Campus Life
  - Subseries 1: Music and Theater
    - Choir 1963-1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Dance 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Dance 1965 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Music 1960 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Music 1960 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Music 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Music 1968-1978 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Opera 1962 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Opera 1962 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Opera 1963 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Theater 1961 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2: Special Events, Award Ceremonies, Graduations
    - Award Ceremonies 1960-1963 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Award Ceremonies 1964 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Founder’s Day 1962 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Graduation 1961 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Graduation 1962 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Graduation 1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Medallion Presentations 1960 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Medallion Presentations 1960-1963 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Parent’s Day 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Parties 1958-1962 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Parties 1962-1980 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Sororities and Fraternities 1960-1962 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Special Visitors including Senator Amherst, Robert Frost, Mexican Consul 1960-1962 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Student Events including debates, practice trials 1963-1967 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Student Events including assemblies 1961-1963 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Student Events including Computercade 1960 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 3: Athletics
    - Basketball Championship 1988 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Football 1958-1960 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Football circa 1980 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Football circa 1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Homecoming 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Homecoming 1960 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Homecoming 1960 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Homecoming 1962-1963 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Women’s Football 1960 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Women’s Swimming 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Women’s Swimming 1962-1964 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Quadrille 1960 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4: People
    - Identified Faculty: Carroll, Gould, Harshburger, Haury, Martin, Patrick, Voris 1960-1963 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Miss Arizona 1960 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Pop McKale 1961 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Presidents, Harvill 1959-1963 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Presidents, Harvill 1963-1964 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Presidents, Schaffer and family 1971 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Students, from Douglas 1960 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Students, foreign 1962-1965 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Students, ROTC 1960-1966 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified Faculty, Staff and Students 1960-1961 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified Faculty, Staff and Students 1962-1964 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Arts and Museums
  - Subseries 1: Art Galleries
    - Art Gallery 1960 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Art Gallery 1960-1961 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Art Gallery 1962 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Art Gallery, includes Native American art displays 1962 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Art Gallery 1962 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Art Gallery 1962 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Art Gallery, includes Gallagher 1962 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Art Gallery 1962 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Art Gallery 1963 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Art Gallery, includes ceramics 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: Art and Museum Objects
    - Miscellaneous objects including silver, portraits, coins, Ed Comitz’s tie clip 1960-1971 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Museum Displays 1959-1965 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Native American arts and crafts 1961 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Native American arts and crafts 1961-1962 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Native American arts and crafts 1971 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Paintings 1958-1963 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Paintings, includes art of Bonnie Swarbrick Moorehouse and Paul Mirocha 1967-1985 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Photos 1960-1975 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Portraits of Mr. Gibson 1963 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Student Work 1962 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Student Work 1963 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Buildings
  - Subseries 1: Buildings
    - Agriculture, interior and exterior 1962 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Agriculture, interior and exterior 1962 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Agriculture, interior and exterior 1962 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Anthropology buildings, includes interior of Tree Ring Lab 1962 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Architecture, interior and exterior 1962-1964 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Chemistry 1966 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Dorms 1958-1963 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Dorms, Men’s, 4th and Highland undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Dorm, Women’s 1963 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Education 1963-1964 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Engineering buildings 1959 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Fine Arts buildings 1963-1967 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Fine Arts buildings 1968 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Law 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Library 1960 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Library 1976 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Old Main 1972 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Park Student Union 1966 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - P.E., Women’s 1964 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Space Sciences building 1966 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - State Museum 1963 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Student Infirmary 1964 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Student Union 1973 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Various Buildings 1959-1964 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Various Buildings, including letter requesting photography job 1966 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Various Buildings 1970 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Various Buildings 1970 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Various Buildings 1970 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Various Buildings undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Various Buildings undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Various Buildings undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Series VII: Various
  - Subseries 1: Various
    - De Grazia’s Art Gallery 1971 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Horses and Riders 1963 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Tombstone, Elgin and Sonoita Soil profiles 1969 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Tucson Medical Center 1958 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Tucson Street Views 1959-1985 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Tubac Dam 1966 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - U.S.S. AZ Bell undated (Box 27, Folder 10)